Friends, if you are going to
take a health insurance policy for yourself or your parents and the
premium is very high, then
in this video I am going to tell you some very important hacks,
if you follow them then
your premium will be reduced by 40 to 50 percent
and you will get the same benefit, so this is a
very important video, you
guys should watch the video till the end, before moving ahead in the video let me
introduce myself to you, my name is
Brijendra Gautam and you are watching ABTech
Financial Advisor Policy Bazaar, we do
health advisory, if you have any
query, any claim then you
can contact us
[praise]
that you should take the policy as soon as possible at a young age
so that you do not have any PD
in the future, you remain secure for that,
let's say if due to some reason you are not
able to take it at that time, then now you are planning health insurance for
yourself and your parents,
so the most important point here is that
see if your premium is very high
then the number one tip for you is that
you can choose the option of
deductible.  30000, 50000, one lakh, whatever
deductible you choose,
you get a discount accordingly. So
suppose you choose a deductible of 50000,
then whenever a claim comes,
you will have to pay an initial amount of 50000 from your pocket once a year
and the company will bear the rest of the expenses.
So what will happen in this? By
choosing a deductible, your premium gets
reduced a lot. Sometimes
your premium gets reduced by 50, 60, 70 percent.
So suppose your earlier premium was
60000, then now it will be 0000 or 35000.
By choosing a deductible, deductible is available in many policies,
so you
can go for the deductible. Let's talk about
tip number two. So see, here many
such health insurance policies have come
where if your civil score is good, then
you get a discount of 5 to 10 percent.
Very few people know that
discount is also given on the basis of civil score.  It is
available, but in reality, there are
health insurance policies available in the market today
that offer discounts based on your CIVIC score.
If you use a credit card
or have taken a loan
and have paid on time, then
obviously your CIVIC score will be good, so
in such a situation you can get this discount.
Tip number three: If you
take a family floater or multi-individual policy,
you also get a family discount.
So, if you are
thinking of taking an individual policy, then include her in the family as well, and
you will get a good discount on that too. Tip number four:
If you have a baby girl in your house, then
if you add her to the policy,
you get an extra discount of up to 5% in her name. So,
whenever you take a family floater policy, always
include the entire family in it, which will give you a
family discount and here
you will also get a discount for the baby girl child.
Tip number five: There are some health policies
which can be taken if you
make a female the proposer, that is, make your wife the proposer,
or women can take the policy in their own name.  If you
take a family floater policy, then a
discount of 5% to 10% is
available for the female proposer as well. So, if you are going to take a family floater
policy, then if you
make your wife the proposer, then you will
get a discount here as well. Tip number six: There are some
health insurance policies in the market
which also give you a discount on vaccination. So,
if you have got the
Covid vaccination done and
you give its certificate to the company or your advisor, then
you get a discount there as well.
Tip number seven, which is very
important, through which you
can get a discount of up to 30%
in the renewal of the health insurance policy. This is
called wellness discount. There are
many such policies available in the market
which give a discount of up to 30% if you remain healthy and walk daily.
So what happens here is that
if you walk 10,000 steps daily,
300 days in a year or 270 days, 250 days, 200
days, 150 days, then according to which you walk 10,000 steps in a year  If you complete
10,000 steps per day,
you
get a discount of up to 30%. For this, you have to
download a simple company app
and
[praise]
google3 will keep counting and
you will get a discount of up to 30% at the time of renewal. So,
I have told you these seven tips which are very important
and with this you
can save a lot of your premium. Now
I am giving you a bonus tip which you
must keep in mind. See, whenever you
take a health insurance policy,
take it at an early age. If you
take a health insurance policy at 20 or 25 years, then
what will happen here, your premium will be very less
because as the age increases, the
chances of getting a disease
increase. Due to this, the
premium increases with the age. Like, there is a
problem later. If you take a policy at an early age, then
you will easily get a cover of 10 lakhs for 6 to 7000. If you have
any query related to health insurance, then you
can contact us.  Yes, you can
also book health insurance policy from us.
Health insurance policies of all companies are available here and
we not only sell the policy but
also help you in getting the claim. Finally, a
small request to you that if you
liked our video then please
like the video and subscribe to the channel
because
we keep bringing similar videos on the channel. That's all for this video.
Thank you.